FARHAN TAUFIK SYABAN

Full Stack Developer

Bandung, Indonesia | Phone: 082148056518 | Email: farhantaufiks@gmail.com

SUMMARY

A Software Developer with 2+ years' Experience Currently in Web Developer both Front End and Back End, Familiar with Oil and Gas Industry Specifically GNG and Petrophysics, also fluent in RESTFUL API, SQL, JS/TS as Programming Language and some Tech Stack used in IT Industry. Proven to have already delivered fully working API made from scratch for database design and server used for webapp and mobile app.

EXPERIENCE

PT. Elektronik Distribusi Otomatisasi Terkemuka (Nabati Group) Bandung, Indonesia

Back End Developer (August 2021 – present)

- Successfully develop API for Logistic business model webapp and mobiles app, starting from Database Design (ERD), until Live in Production (Feb 2022) using NestJS as Framework and MySQL as Database, all from scratch.
- Understanding differences between multiple platforms such as mobile (iOS & android) vs desktop and optimizing output to match the specific platform.
- Managing Live Server while also doing weekly maintenance (Feb 2022 present), looking for improvement in optimizing resources both speed and usage, while also developing feature requested by user.
- Doing Bug Fixing and developing some features for Front End in WebApp due to lack of resources while not ignoring the responsibility in backend side.
- Successfully Develop major feature on others Business Unit App (Food business model and Core Internal API) while using different Tech Stack and Programming Language (Golang).
- Successfully develop integration with other Business Model (Food) to use internal Logistic App as delivery courrier in Food App, doing this generate gmv for both logistic and food, while also reducing dependencies with others delivery courier and its enabler.
- Successfully develop different flow model from existing in logistic (B2C) to connect sisters' company in Nabati Group (Kaldu Sari Nabati Indonesia and Pinus Merah Abadi) with existing Logistic App as new flow introduced which is B2B.

PT Panda Advis Teknologi (Pandatech)

Jakarta, Indonesia

Front End Developer (June 2021 – August 2021)

- Develop new user facing features, Mobile (iOS android) and Web (CMS), for fitness platform app.
- Write reusable code and libraries, using functional components, and modify "antd" to match what uiux define.
- Develop responsive new design web, for influencer app vybes (responsive all devices)

EDUCATION

HACKTIV8 INDONESIA (2021)

Full stack JavaScript Developer Program - Grade 100.47 (Teacher's Award / Excellent)

• 4 Months Intensive learning from preparation phase for fundamental programming, and Bootcamp for hard & soft skill required to be full stack developer.

UNIVERSITAS PADJADARAN (2015 - 2019)

Bachelor of Geological Engineering - GPA 3.60

SKILLS

- Front End
 - ReactJS, React Native, VueJS
- Back End
 - NodeJS, Typescript using Nest, Golang using GRPC, Redis, ORM (Typeorm, Sequelize), SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL), NoSQL (MongoDB)
- Dev Ops
 - AWS (Ec2, S3, RDS), Firebase, Docker, Gitlab Ci-CD